Look, Ioryogi! What a cute kitty!
I need a home.
Take me!
You don't need to keep wasting your time on crap like that.
It's so fluffy!
What did I just tell you!?
I can't let a kitten go lonely!
So what are you gonna do about it?
This!
This way the kitty won't be lonely and I can still look for people to heal!
Do you want to be stuck here your whole life?
What shall I do?
Even the obvious things are always so hard
I just want to grin when I'm happy, sing when I'm in love
They say my dreams will come true someday
but when will someday come? I can't wait!
Count one, two, three and spread my arms
Gather the light to myself
Where is it? Tell me what I can do
Even if I'm hurt so much, even if I run so hard
Even if I collapse crying over and over, I still
believe in my amazing future
... A kitten's lullabye.
You can't even take care of yourself,
and you want to look after a kitten? Don't make me laugh!
I can't just ignore her!
What, a stray cat this time?
Wrong! Its owner just couldn't care for it anymore!
That's the same thing!
You shouldn't even start if you're not ready to commit to taking care of it.
You're so mean.
He's right, though, isn't he?
Kitty?
What is it?
It's probably hungry.
What's the answer to number 5, Chiho?
You don't get it either, Chise?
Hello?
It's Kobato!
Hi!
I need food!
Mama went out for a while, this is all we have.
Maybe something a little more than a snack...
It's not for me.
It's for this kitty!
Wow, it's cute!
Its owner can't take care of it anymore...
So i thought maybe you could help.
Can we go to your room, Kobato?
Sure.
She's enjoying it.
That's great.
Why are you two being so quiet?
Mama doesn't allow pets here.
One of the tenants before had a dog, and the neighbors complained about its barking.
So she isn't taking new tenants with pets anymore.
So you can't really take care of it here.
Why not go back to the owner?
I don't know who it is.
I found her in a box.
It didn't have the owner's name on it.
I see. But you can't keep it here.
I hope you can find someone to take care of it.
I'll ask Miss Sayaka tomorrow at Yomogi Nursery!
I'm sure Sayaka would agree!
And if it's at Yomogi we can go see her anytime!
You should probably give her a name, then.
What do you think, Kobato?
Me?
Umm...
It's too sudden! I can't think of anything!
She's white all over, so maybe Milk?
Plus, she loves drinking it.
Milk, huh? That's a cute name.
It's wonderful!
It's so white and cute!
She's called Milk.
Here, Milk!
I want to hold her too!
Me too!
Let me feel her!
Everyone's having so much fun.
So can we keep her?
Come over here, Yuzuru.
Are you okay?
Yuzuru, are you allergic to cats?
Allergic to cats?
People who are sneeze and their skin breaks out.
If it's really bad, it can even trigger asthma.
Miss Sayaka...
We can't keep cats here at Yomogi.
You're right.
Sorry, Kobato.
When you just up and do things like that, it makes trouble for everyone else.
It wasn't just a whim!
Why not take care of it yourself?
Fujimoto!
If you're just going to take things halfway so you can be self-satisfied,
you're as bad as the guy who abandoned her to begin with.
Sorry, Kobato.
I'm feeling better now, so-
No, I'm sorry!
Stop it!
Quit playing with me! Just because I'm a stuffed animal doesn't mean that's all I am!
Oh, there you are, Kobato.
Miss Sayaka?
Mind if I sit next to you?
Go ahead.
Sorry to get you down like that.
No, I'm sorry.
Fujimoto wasn't trying to be mean either.
I think... That kitten kind of reminded him of himself.
Anyway, I'll look for someone who can take care of it too.
It'll be okay. I'm sure we'll find someone.
Okay.
So what are you going to do now?
I'll look for someone who'll take care of Milk!
That way I won't cause any trouble for everyone!
Yeah, I agree. It'll make my life easier.
Bye-bye!
Sayaka!
Hi!
Is Milk here?
A cat allergy?
Yes. I'm sorry.
No, don't worry.
Maybe we should ask Mama?
We can't, pets aren't allowed.
If we do, she'll really be in a tough spot.
Yeah.
Won't someone take this kitty in?
Please, take care of this kitty!
Please, help this kitty!
Kobato!
Chiho, Chise.
Here, Milk!
Have you been a good girl?
I'm sorry, I asked Miss Sayaka, but...
We heard about it from her.
It's not your fault, Kobato.
But I can't find anyone else to take her.
We'll help out!
I'm sure we'll find a new owner for Milk!
Sorry, I have my hands full with just the kids.
What's wrong, Catharine?
Let's go, Kobato.
Sorry!
Another one of you annoying salesmen!?
Huh?
Milk!
Domoto.
Kobato?
Here, Milk!
Wow, that's great!
So you're looking for someone to take care of her...
Yeah.
Pretty much everyone I know lives alone...
I don't know how fast I'll be, but I'll help out too.
Thank you.
Sorry to bother you all.
I'm not bothered.
After all, you're so serious about it.
It makes everyone want to help you.
That's...
But maybe we should stop knocking on strangers' doors.
But Fujimoto said that if I do things halfway just to be self-satisfied,
I'm just like the person who abandoned her.
That's Kiyokazu for you. You shouldn't let him get to you.
I don't think there's anyone who'd want to get rid of a cute kitty.
I'm sure there must have been a reason.
Fujimoto seemed so lonely then...
It's just like he said. I can't take it halfway.
I've got to do all I can!
This time I'll ask everyone I know.
If you have any trouble, just give me a call.
Sure. Thanks!
Looks like they're out.
They're closed.
I'm busy with the cooking, I don't have time for a cat.
I see.
Sorry I couldn't help you out.
Hello, Mihara residence.
Sayaka?
A kitten?
I wanted to keep it here, but...
That happened with the kids.
I understand. Talk to you later.
Huh?
It's getting pretty dark, isn't it.
Milk's getting tired.
Milk?
She must be hungry!
All right!
This one!
I'm so worthless. I can't do anything.
You can't even buy cat food!
I know...
Hey, Chise.
What?
We really should ask Mama.
Yeah. I'm sure she'd let us get away with it.
Then we can sleep with Milk tonight!
You should sleep over too, Kobato!
Sure.
That's that-
Oh my.
You're the young lady who sang so beautifully.
Do you know her, Kobato?
Yeah.
How's the baby doing?
His mommy had the day off, so she's spending it with him.
I see.
But why are you here?
I heard there was a girl looking for a home for her kitty.
Oh my.
It must be this one.
She's so tiny and cute.
I can take care of her if you want.
Really!?
Yeah. My grandson is an only child, so he'll have someone to play with.
But...
There's people who sneeze and break out when they touch a cat.
Will a baby be okay around her?
The pizza boy from before was worried about the same thing.
The pizza boy?
Yeah. He was insisting the person he delivered to take her.
I overheard him while passing by, and that's why I came here.
That was Fujimoto...
My grandson loves animals.
He won't have any problem with allergies.
Oh my.
That's great, Milk.
You won't be alone anymore.
Anyway...
Bye-bye, Milk!
We'll come see you sometime!
Wait!
This is Milk's dinner!
Thank you very much.
Take good care of her, okay?
Please?
It feels so empty in here without Milk.
I feel refreshed!
That's Milk's milk dish.
Chiho and Chise must feel the same way.
Where are you going?
Kobato?
Good evening!
Um...
The twins are up on the roof.
She must be treating Milk well.
She seemed so kind.
I'm sure they'll be fine.
Kobato?
That's...
I forgot to bring it back earlier.
It's Milk's-
Milk dish...
Yeah.
Now that I think of it, it was a full moon when I first met her.
The cherry blossoms were so beautiful.
She had gone for a walk with a baby, and he wouldn't stop crying.
I tried to heal him, but...
He just kept crying!
And then?
What happened?
Then I sang a song.
You sing, Kobato?
Yes.
When I did, he stopped crying.
What kind of song was it?
Umm...
I wanna hear it!
Me too!
Let us hear it, Kobato!
Please!
Okay.
The flowers which blossom in spring
Are plucked in the summer sun
Within my heart
Their shine remains
Even on days I close my windows
To shut out the morning rain
Fluttering within my heart
The light breaks through the clouds
A faraway voice leads me on
Like it's smiling, like it's singing
The echoing sound of the wind
Joy and sadness
I embrace them both and keep going
My hand and yours
Join together strongly
What is it?
Thanks for doing that for Milk.
She found a great new owner because of you.
Is that all you needed?
Yes!
What are you doing!?
I just remembered something important!
Can I borrow your phone?
Anyway, give me a call if you find a cat-lover.
Thanks.
Kiyokazu?
Hello?
Umm... Well...
Kobato? What's up?
The kitty found a new owner!
I just wanted to let you know.
I see.
Fujimoto found her one.
Kiyokazu?
I see.
Sorry to bother you with it.
That's great, though.
Anyway, later.
There's another one.
But why?
Fujimoto's the one who found Milk a new owner.
I didn't do anything.
You did nothing,
except drag a kitten around and bother everyone.
Yeah... Everyone worried so much because of me...
But there's a give-and-take.
Just like everything in life.
When you let her go, you realized Chiho and Chise's loneliness,
and sang for them.
I was just trying to tell them about the baby and his grandmother!
That was enough to cheer them up.
Songs can heal people's hearts, huh.
But.
They won't heal my scarred ear!
So zero points for you, Kobato!
But... It's round, just like the moon tonight!
Don't get so happy about it!
Oh, and Milk's dish was round too!
They all match!
All right, if you like round things so much, I'll be sure to give you plenty more zeroes!
You're so mean, Ioryogi!
People all want to fly
but they're cheated by gravity
everyone can really fly
She must be so unhappy because
she forgot her own shadow somewhere
Then...
If you tell me "thanks", if you say "thanks" and smile
Going back and forth, we'll be happy
You'll be happy, there'll be nothing to worry about
As long as we're together
It's strange, I'm crying even though I'm happy
... Summer memories.
Next episode